# Bjørnar Moe Remmen

A developer with experiences within machine learning and backend development. As a developer I really like the challenge machine learning gives and the ability to be creative. The last year I also completed a course in Parallel Programming covering CUDA, OpenMPI and basic pthread & openmp use.

## **Experience**

## Microchip

Application Engineer • Aug, 2020 — Present

Writing software both for microcontrollers in C and general backend development.

## Capgemini

Data Scientist • Jan, 2019 — Aug, 2020

Worked with a team that specializing in Computer Vision. One of my projects at a startup that used underwater cameras in fish farms was to try to create a program to monitor the health of the fish using Computer Vision.

## **Making Waves**

Data Scientist • Jul, 2017 — Dec, 2018

Worked as a general developer and Data Scientist. Two of the projects including Machine Learning were a Norwegian Chatbot project in python and Proof of Concept testing Computer Vision in Elastic Search.

### Kodeklubben Trondheim

Instructor - Internship • Jun, 2016 — Jul, 2016

Kodeklubben is a Norwegian initative to teach children coding. This internship was about teaching HTMl, CSS, JavaScript to people from junior high school and high school.

## **Education**

## Norwegian University of Science and Technology - NTNU

Informatics, M.Sc., Artificial Intelligence • 2015 — 2017

## Sør-Trøndelag University COllege - HiST

Computer Science, B.Sc. • 2012 − 2015

## **Projects**

#### SEALAB OCEAN GROUP

Developer • March 2019 — August 2019

Sealab is a provider of under water cameras that is used in fish farming for monitoring fish. To be able to monitor the fishes health, I was a consultant helping to get further in the computer vision goal of monitoring fish and wounds.

## Matprat.no — Chatbot in Norwegian

Developer • March 2018 - June 2018

Matprat is a food recipe website, and the end result provided for them was a chatbot that could answer food safety questions and give suggetions on what to make based on what ingredients the person has. The reason do do this was to give a better user experience for the user when looking for recipes and to avoid food waste.

## **Skills**

#### Parallel Progamming

Took a course in 2020 at NTNU in parallel rogramming that covered CUDA, OpenMPI, OpenMP and Pthreads. Implemented Convolution in OpenMPI and CUDA getting Ideas from the paper Ghost Cell Pattern

## Recognition

## Global Data Science Challenge 2020 - 1st place

Capgemini • 2020

The Capgemini Data Science Challenge was a colaboration between Amazon and Capgemini. The challenge was to identify sperm whales by their fluke to help to monitor the whales.

## **Associations**

#### **School Bar**

*Volunteer* • 2001 — 2010

The School bar is used by both engineers and other diciplines to socialize. Some responsibilities I had were to work behind the bar and checking IDs at the entrance.

## **Additional Links**

• Capgemini Global Datascience Challenge - Using AI to protect sperm whales

## **Social Links**

- **LinkedIn**: https://www.linkedin.com/in/bjornarremm resume\_pdf\_url
- Website: https://github.com/bjornamr/resume-template/raw/gh-pages/webpage/resume.pdf